Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Deploy the main wings !
Main wing power offline !
Unable to deploy !
8,000 till Gatlantis !
Chief Engineer !
No response from the engine !
Urgent message from the Antares !
"We're right behind the Yamato, but can't stay much
longer because we're approaching the critical escape line."
"Leave the ship by any means possible !"
Okita...
...sorry.
All hands...
Abandon ship !
The ship is being pulled into the enemy's
gravitational field due to engine failure !
All departments, follow evacuation protocols !
Leave the ship immediately and get to the Antares !
No...
Shima...
No, I want to stay...
No objections !
Shima...
Everyone feels the same,
including Captain Hijikata...
But if we don't leave, the other
crew members will hesitate.
We have to go.
That's a team leader's responsibility.
Mr. Tokugawa...
Critical escape line approaching.
Remaining time for escape, 6-0-0.
First Officer Sanada take starboard !
Chief Tactical Officer Kodai take port !
Lead the crew evacuation !
Aye, sir !
Chief Engineer Tokugawa, follow protocol and lock down the wave motion engine.
Sir.
Cosmo Tigers and all remaining ships on board, take what
personnel you can, leave the ship, and head for the Antares !
All hands, evacuate quickly !
Don't hesitate !
Do your best to survive !
The war has just begun !
Each of you must live to
support the future of Earth !
Kato !
Lieutenant Keyman !
Whatever you do, it's no use.
Don't say that !
Come on, stand up !
Hurry !
Help me, please !
Auxiliary power is below 10%.
Losing ship interior gravity.
First Officer Sanada !
Reaching the critical escape line.
On board craft no longer have enough power to escape.
Antares, this is Yamato.
Crew evacuation is complete.
Turn around immediately, and leave.
Take care.
The Antares has recovered all ships
from the Yamato and is escaping !
The Yamato is falling toward the interior of the Comet Empire and we've lost communication !
Yamato, I'm sure...
High dimensional energy signatures
coming from the Comet Empire !
Missiles !
Come about 180 degrees and break away at once !
Is that...?
A massive wave motion shield...
Could that be...?
Ginga
I won't let you get through...
...Gatlantis !
On behalf of the almighty Emperor Zorder,
I deliver this message to the leader of Earth.
I confirm receipt of Earth's response.
I admire your determination to fight until the end.
I will put up a worthy fight, but before that...
...allow me to send you a gift.
I've heard a number of children are suffering from a
terminal illness as a result of the war against Garmillas.
I'm sending you data for medicine that can cure it.
By using it, you should be able to
save those who have this fatal illness.
I present it to you as a reward
for a certain Earth soldier's love.
The Commander couldn't evacuate.
Same for Nagakura...
...Kodai, Operations Chief Mori, and even the Gamie.
What the hell are you doing ?!
Let me die !
Please let me die !
First Lieutenant Kato says
he'll accept any punishment.
I beg you...
You can't be serious.
The public must not know...
...that a warrior of the Yamato betrayed his ship,
even if it was because of his love for his child.
Keep tight-lipped about this.
If he wants to atone for his sins,
he can die in battle.
MAIN SHAFT Elevator
Sir, are you alright ?
I'm fine, but the Yamato...
It's similar.
It's a Yamato-class after all.
Route to the mission area determined.
First Officer Kanzaki, here's the
route from the Command A.I.
Approved and shared.
Everything goes like that.
The Ginga is a prototype for the next generation of ships that
are potentially capable of A.I. equipped autonomous operation.
The future is extreme.
It's nothing but efficiency.
All humans have to do is
approve the A.I.'s decisions, huh ?
That's inevitable.
Welcome aboard the Federation Space Cruiser Ginga.
I'm the captain, Todo Saki.
First and foremost, please come
to the central operations room.
As you know, the Garmillas shield is capable of preventing warp by nullifying Gatlantis's dimensional jump ability.
Our primary mission is to protect the Garmillas shield, but the second wave of the attack will be a problem.
There are many vessels with
dual annihilation missiles.
If the shield is breached,
Earth will be in grave danger.
So, I proposed a surprise attack
with a small group of elite soldiers.
Using the Ginga's wave motion shield,
we will attack the enemy vanguard...
...and destroy it before they
can regroup with the main force.
To perfect the plan...
...the next generation A.I. is undergoing a continuous self-growth simulation in the Time Fault...
...simultaneously improving the
Ginga's A.I. with the latest data.
Even so, it'll take time to
surpass human experience.
So, I'd like the Yamato crew to provide your
knowledge and experience to improve the Ginga's A.I.
Copy our knowledge ?
You'll be assigned to the primary and secondary bridges, and all your actions will be recorded.
I have approval from HQ, of course.
It's essential to the success of Plan G.
Plan G ?
The Yamato was lost.
In order for mankind to survive,
we've transferred the Yamato's DNA to this ship.
I propose activation of CRS.
Approved.
Ginga, maximum combat speed.
Enemy fleet is in motion.
CRS efficiency, 80%.
Wave motion energy injected. Initiating boost.
All ships, wave motion
core resonance confirmed.
Wave motion shield output has
exceeded 750,000 TPa and rising.
I didn't know the Cosmo Reverse
System was capable of this.
The heart of this ship came from the Yamato.
It doesn't have the ability to restore a planet, but it's an ideal device for controlling wave motion energy.
A wave motion gun isn't equipped, is it ?
The Cosmo Reverse rejects it.
Not just the wave motion gun, but our conventional weapons malfunction if we try to use it.
The cause is unknown, so we have to rely on our escort fleet for all combat, including self-defense.
That's how it should be.
I designed the Ginga for exploration.
Even so, we have to use it this way...
Wave motion shield is
weakening at a rate of 8,000.
We should move forward and
enter the escort fleet's firing range.
Bombardment is ineffective
with our current firepower.
Suggest Operation Black Bird.
Approved.
Black Bird...
Unmanned craft are already...
Each Black Bird is equipped with bombs made from a mass-produced wave motion core.
We'll deploy them to the center of the enemy fleet, then amplify them with the Ginga's Cosmo Reverse causing an overload.
The resulting wave motion resonance
will disable the enemy fleet...
The Yamato used the same
strategy at the 11th Planet.
But even with the latest A.I., how do we
get to the center of the enemy fleet...
Correct. A skilled pilot
volunteered to lead the way.
Don't tell me, it's Kato...?
That's suicide !
He'll be attacked from all directions
once he leaves the warp interference area !
We'll hold the enemy advancement
for 10 days at our current combat strength.
During that time, 100 days will pass in the Time Fault,
allowing us to finish several dozen wave motion ships.
We'll hold for another 10 days by deploying the new ships, then again and again...
If we repeat this, it won't matter
how strong our enemy is...
What about the people ?!
The crew won't be able to...
We're very close to
building an unmanned fleet...
...and the Ginga and the Black Birds prove that.
The creation of artificial human soldiers is becoming
real thanks to the data sampled from Gatlantian soldiers.
100 days...
...if we can just hold for 100 days...
The wave motion cores are getting
shot down, and decreasing in number !
Emergency proposal,
start the resonance immediately.
Withdraw the Black Bird squadron !
Black Bird squadron, retreat immediately !
Kato !
Begin resonance ?
Approved.
Ginga
Wave motion energy injected.
This is insane.
You can't win a war with sanity.
Eliminate unnecessary items and
make use of anything useful...
...for effective and swift victory.
That's Plan G, huh ?
No, Plan G is...
Are you alright with this, Captain Todo ?
Given your mother's circumstances,
I understand how you feel...
...but deep down, you...
Don't.
This has nothing to do
with my father or mother.
It's none of your business, Kaoru.
The weak will perish.
We learned that the hard way
during the war against Garmillas.
No matter what I lose, I must...
Why...?
Why won't you let me die ?!
What's wrong ?
Nothing.
I thought I heard someone crying.
Must be the sound of the wind.
Yeah...
This is Keyman.
The fog is getting thicker.
Can you see anything from up there ?
Nothing.
We'll circle around a little longer.
You go back to the ship.
It's dangerous to fly in this fog.
Roger.
Where are we ?
We're supposed to be
inside the White Comet, right ?
But I don't think a Gatlantis base could
operate on an empty planet like this.
Maybe we were tossed onto a planet
several thousand light years away.
Layers of limited information
can mess with your perception.
Hey, you jerk...
Of all places...
Could it be Teresa's guidance ?
That planet is still alive.
If it responds to the blood of the Zemurian...
I know, but those lives have no future.
Who's there ?
Who are you ?
What the...?
How ironic.
Yuki !
Yuki.
I'm glad you're awake.
You should stay in bed.
I'll call Dr. Sado...
Who...?
Who are you ?
Episode 19
Yamato's Successor Bears the Name of Ginga
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Niimi Kaoru:
Kato Saburo:
Yamamoto Akira:
Analyzer:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Hisakawa Aya
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Tanaka Rie
Cho
Katsuragi Touko:
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Amagi Toshio:
Kurata Masaru:
Hijikata Ryu:
Kishida Yu:
Yamazaki Susumu:
Hoshina Yuria:
Kiryu Mikage:
Hoshina Toru:
Kaida Yuko
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Saito Jiro
Yoshikai Kiyohito
Ishizuka Unsho
Shimada Hiroshi
Tsuchida Hiroshi
Uchida Aya
Nakamura Eriko
Takagi Motoki
Cottony clouds drift high across the sky
Sora takaku nagareru kieyuku wata no kumo
Todo Saki:
Kanzaki Megumi:
Kusakabe Urara:
A.I.:
Yamanami Osamu:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Klaus Keyman:
Zorder:
Gailane:
Genitz:
Andromeda XO:
Andromeda Comm Officer:
Takagaki Ayahi
Hayashibara Megumi
Komiya Arisa
Cho
Ebara Masashi
Genda Tessho
Kamiya Hiroshi
Tezuka Hideaki
Shibata Hidekatsu
Umetsu Hideyuki
Ichinose Hiroaki
Fujimura Kento
Holding out both hands, I stretch out in the falling leaves
Ryoote wo age ah senobi shita rakuyou
As the house lights come on, I wish to meet people smiling at each other
Akari tomoru mado waraiau hito ni aitai to omou
Believing in a miraculous enounter to become real, I shout out for love
Sou kanau hazusa kiseki no deai ni ai sakenda
Luminous lives meet and bond with each other
Kagayaku jinsei no meguriawase tsumuideyuku
Let’s keep on living our lives
Bokura no jinsei wo tayumazu ni susumi tsuzukeyou
Let’s begin the story of our lives
Bokura no jinsei no monogatari wo saa hajimeyou
Preview
Are you...
She lost the memories of the last 4 years ?
Why...?
Are you going to raise the dead ?
I'll save the Yamato no matter what.
Let's end our suffering.
Episode 20
Gatlantis, the Cursed Children